// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The maximum number of electrons which can occupy 2s orbital is",
    answer: "2",
    options: [
      "1",
      "2",
      "3",
      "4"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The lightest particle is",
    answer: "positron",
    options: [
      "positron",
      "neutron",
      "proton",
      "hydrogen"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "the shape of s-orbitales is",
    answer: "spherical",
    options: [
      "dumb-bells",
      "triangle",
      "spherical",
      "double dumbbell"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "lowest oxidation state in its compound is exhibited by",
    answer: "flourine",
    options: [
      "nitrogen",
      "oxygen",
      "carbon",
      "flourine"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "which of the following is most covalent in nature",
    answer: "Alcl3",
    options: [
      "Nacl",
      "mgcl2",
      "cacl2",
      "Alcl3"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "hybridization is methane molecule is",
    answer: "sp^3",
    options: [
      "sp",
      "sp^2",
      "sp^3",
      "sp^3d"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 7,
    question: "the number of moles of a solute per kilogram of the solvent is called",
    answer: "molality",
    options: [
      "formality",
      "normality",
      "molarity",
      "molality"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 8,
    question: "the molarity is defined as the number of most of solute present in",
    answer: "1 litre of the solution",
    options: [
      "1 litre of the solvent",
      "1 litre of the solution",
      "1 kilogram of the solvent",
      "1 kilogram of the solution"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 9,
    question: "The weight percentage of a solute is given by",
    answer: "wt of the solute/wt of the solution*100",
    options: [
      "wt of the solvent/wt of the solute*100 ",
      "wt of the solute/wt of the solvent*100",
      "wt of the solute/wt of the solution*100",
      "wt of the solvent/wt of the solute*100"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The PH value of 0.05M Ba(OH2)sol is",
    answer: "13",
    options: [
      "10",
      "12",
      "13",
      "11"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Pintu Louis theory, acid specify will",
    answer: "Accept electrons",
    options: [
      "Donate electrons",
      "Accept electrons",
      "Accept proton",
      "Donate proton"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 12,
    question: "The conjugate base of hydrogen molecules is",
    answer: "hybrid iron",
    options: [
      "electron",
      "hydrogen ion",
      "proton",
      "hybrid iron"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Salt bridge contains",
    answer: "all the above",
    options: [
      "Agar-Agar",
      "KNO3+KCL",
      "NH4NO3+KCL",
      "all the above"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Galvanic cell are the cells which convert",
    answer: "chemical to electrical energy",
    options: [
      "electrical to chemical energy",
      "chemical to electrical energy",
      "chemical to free energy",
      "potential to kinetic energy"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 15,
    question: "charge associated with one mole of",
    answer: "96500 coulombs",
    options: [
      "96500 coulombs",
      "6.023*10^23 coulombs",
      "965*10^23 coulombs",
      "3*10^23 coulombs"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 16,
    question: "hardness of water is expressed in terms of equivalent of",
    answer: "caco3",
    options: [
      "Na2CO3",
      "Mgco3",
      "k2CO3",
      "caco3"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 17,
    question: "zeolite softeming process removes",
    answer: "both perminant and temporary hardness of water",
    options: [
      "only perminant hardness of water",
      "only temporary hardness of water",
      "both perminant and temporary hardness of water",
      "the dissolved gases in perminant hard water"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 18,
    question: "Hardwater contains",
    answer: "dissolved calcium & magnessium salts",
    options: [
      "small stones",
      "oli",
      "dissolved calcium & magnessium salts",
      "Bacteria"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 19,
    question: "which of the following metal undergoes corrosion easily",
    answer: "Fe",
    options: [
      "Fe",
      "Cu",
      "Mg",
      "Ag"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 20,
    question: "corrosion can be reduced by",
    answer: "alloying",
    options: [
      "Applying stress",
      "adding little impurity",
      "exposing to O2",
      "alloying"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 21,
    question: "corrosion of iron is called",
    answer: "resting",
    options: [
      "roasting",
      "smelting",
      "resting",
      "calcination"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 22,
    question: "The monomer used in PVC preparation is",
    answer: "chloro ethene ",
    options: [
      "ethene",
      "chloro ethene",
      "di-chloroethene",
      "Tetra-chloroethene"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 23,
    question: "Ion exchange resin are made of",
    answer: "propylene ",
    options: [
      "Isoprene",
      "propylene",
      "propane",
      "Ethelene"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 24,
    question: "The first plastic ever synthesized was called ",
    answer: "Bakelite",
    options: [
      "Bakelite",
      "Nylon",
      "dacron",
      "cellulose"
    ]
  }, {
    numb: 25,
    question: "natural fuels are",
    answer: "liquid ",
    options: [
      "primary",
      "secondary",
      "solid",
      "liquid"
    ]
  },

];